<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./send_to_power_bi.png" type="Sink"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Send to Power BI</name>
	<shortDescription>Send a table to Microsoft Power BI.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node sends the input table to Microsoft Power BI.
			<p />
			The node only
			uploads columns that are supported by Power BI. Other
			columns are
			ignored. The supported types are
			<i>String</i>
			,
			<i>Number (integer)</i>
			,
			<i>Number (long)</i>
			,
			<i>Number (double)</i>
			,
			<i>Boolean value</i>
			,
			<i>Local Date</i>
			and
			<i>Local Date Time</i>
			.
			<p />
			The node uploads rows in chunks to Microsoft Power BI. If the node is
			canceled, the already uploaded rows will remain in the Power BI
			dataset.
			<p />
			Use the "Microsoft Authentication" node to connect to your Microsoft account.
			The KNIME
			Analytics Platform Azure Application needs the following
			permissions for this node:
			<ul>
				<li>
					<b>View all datasets</b>
					: Needed to check if a dataset already exists in your Power BI
					workspace.
				</li>
				<li>
					<b>Read and write all datasets</b>
					: Needed to upload a table to a Power BI dataset in your workspace.
				</li>
				<li>
					<b>View all workspaces</b>
					: Needed to get the identifier of the selected Power BI workspace.
				</li>
				<li>
					<b>Maintain access to data you have given it access to</b>
					: Needed to access the Power BI API during the node execution
					without asking you to log in again.
				</li>
			</ul>
			<b>Note:</b>
			The Power BI REST API has some limitations in terms of the size of a
			dataset and the number of rows that can be shipped per hour. For more
			information visit the
			<a
				href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/power-bi/developer/api-rest-api-limitations">documentation</a>
			.
		</intro>
		<tab name="Settings">
			<option name="Workspace">
				Select the workspace to use. Select "default" to use the default
				workspace which is called "My workspace" in the Power BI user
				interface.
				<br />
				<b>NOTE:</b>
				To see the workspace options you have to be authenticated.
			</option>
			<option name="Create new Dataset">
				Select this option to create a new dataset in the selected Power BI workspace.
			</option>
			<option name="Select existing Dataset">
				Select this option to append the input tables to an existing dataset
				or to overwrite all rows of a table of an existing dataset.
				Note that the dataset has to be a
				<a
					href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/power-bi/service-real-time-streaming#types-of-real-time-datasets">"Push dataset"</a>
				for this option to work.
			</option>
			<option name="Dataset name">
				The name of the dataset to create.
			</option>
			<option name="Table name">
				The name of the table in the dataset to upload. If multiple tables are
				uploaded a name has to be configured for each table and the names have
				to be unique.
			</option>
			<option name="Delete and create new if dataset exists">
				Select this option to delete a dataset with the same name if one exists
				before creating the new dataset. If a dataset with the configured name
				exists but this option is not selected the node will fail.
				<br />
				<b>NOTE: All reports and dashboard tiles containing data from the
					dataset will also be deleted.
				</b>
			</option>
			<option name="Append/Overwrite rows">
				Select if the input tables should be appended to the existing tables or
				if all rows of the exiting table should be deleted and overwritten by
				the input rows.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Microsoft Connection">
			Microsoft Connection that provides user authentication.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Table">
			Data to be send to Power BI.
		</inPort>
		<dynInPort insert-before="2" group-identifier="input" name="Additional input table">
			Additional data to be send to your data set.
		</dynInPort>
 </ports>
</knimeNode>